塞勒姆前情回顾
Previously on "Salem"...
不管有没有你的帮助
I will find Mercy Lewis
我都会找到默茜 路易斯
with or without your help.
你是说我是
Are you saying that I am...
一个女巫
A witch.
明天我会
Tomorrow I shall bring
向委员会提交约翰 奥尔登的案子
John Alden's case before the board.
他是无辜的
He is innocent.
你是知道的
And you know it.
遵从因克里斯 麦哲的指令
By order of Increase Mather,
我宣布将你逮捕
I place you under arrest.
我决定为奥尔登上尉辩护
I've decided to defend Captain Alden.
辩护吗
To defend?
让小孩子们都到我这里吧
Let the little children come unto me,
因为魔鬼之国属于他们
for the kingdom of the Devil belongs to them.
来吧
Come.
坐这儿吧 可怜的孩子
Sit here, poor boy.
可怜的 可爱的小男孩 你帮家人工作而劳累致死
Poor, sweet boy, worked to death by your family.
你生命中的每日每夜
Every day of your life,
使你不配埋葬在墓地
making you unfit for burial in the churchyard,
所以他们把你抛尸于此
so they dumped you here.
爱丽丝
Alice.
怀了舅父的孩子
Died in child birth,
最后死于分娩
pregnant from your mother's brother.
在那边 那儿 那个婴儿
There. There, the baby.
被闷死以隐藏证据
Smothered to hide the evidence.
让母亲和孩子在一起吧
Let mother and child be together.
现在我就是你的母亲
I am your mother now.
你们所有人
All of you!
你们都是我的孩子
And you all are my children.
我的父亲 深受尊敬的路易斯牧师
My father, the good Reverend Lewis,
说这世上没有炼狱
said that there is no purgatory,
迷失在天堂和地狱之间的灵魂没有居所
no place for souls lost between heaven and hell.
但是他错了
But he was wrong.
地球就是炼狱
Earth is purgatory.
我们就是晃荡在这片土地上的鬼魂
We are the ghosts that haunt this land.
不 默茜
No, Mercy.
你还好好的活着呢
You are very much alive.
也许比我们中的任何一个人都更活生生的
Perhaps more alive than any of us.
但是你像个幽灵一样隐藏了自己
Yet you have hidden yourself like a ghost.
因克里斯在到处搜寻你
Increase searches everywhere for you.
他永远也不会找到这里
He will never look here.
但是我的女孩们
But my girls.
我可怜的女孩们怎么办
What of my poor girls?
他抓到了其中四个
He has four of them.
但你不用担心她们或你自己
But do not fear for them or yourself.
很快我们盛大的仪式将净化这片土地上的邪恶之事
Soon our grand rite will cleanse this land of the evil men do
和行邪恶之事的邪恶之人
and the men who do it,
就像圣经时代的大洪水
like the great flood of biblical times,
为我们的新世界开路
making way for our new world.
尽管放心吧 默茜
And rest assured, Mercy --
你 你的女孩们
you, your girls,
和你的孩子们都会在那有立足之地
and all your children shall have a place there.
噢 谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
但告诉我
But tell me --
告诉我 也许我就能消除她们的恐惧
tell me so I may reassure them in their fear.
是什么事
What is it?
将要发生什么
What is coming?
死亡
Death.
视频字幕由 SSK字幕组 制作发布
字幕只供学习 请勿做任何商业行为
敬请关注新浪微博@SSK字幕组
翻译：小泥 Espionage shooky elsa 小A
校对：柯小南 慕斯 爱吃      后期：D
总监：男琪琪 Bezero      时轴：络睿
塞勒姆
第一季  第十二集
这是一个古老的真理
'Tis an ancient proverbial truth
只要有一颗烂苹果在 就会烂掉一整筐
that it requires but one dead apple to rot an entire barrel.
我也渐渐相信只需一个烂苹果
And I come to believe it requires but one apple
就能让整片土地腐烂
to make this whole land equally rotten.
但不是随便的哪颗苹果
And not just any apple,
而是潘多拉魔盒
but the malum.
苹果的形状
The icon of the apple
几乎贯穿了我们所见的有关盛大的仪式的每个画面
runs through almost every image we have of the grand rite.
盛大的仪式带来了死亡
The grand rite brings about death,
大规模死亡
death on a mass scale.
我们对它的运作几乎都不了解
We know little of its operation,
也不了解释放了随之而来的死亡
nor the -- the mechanism of magic
的魔法的奥秘
that unleashes the -- the death that follows.
只有这一句莫明其妙又简单的话
Only this one enigmatically simple sentence --
魔盒开启
"Malum est aperta."
邪恶降临
"The evil begins."
但这么多年我一直在误读
But I have been misreading it all these years.
我们都理解错了 包括我的父亲
We all have, my father included.
魔盒的意思是邪恶 但同样也是苹果
"Malum" Means "Evil," But equally "Apple."
现在我相信这个句子应该读做
And I now believe the sentence to read,
苹果开启
"The apple opens,"
同时它又暗示 要释放其必然的结果 那就是死亡
and, by implication, unleashes the death that results.
我相信我已经看到过那个苹果
I believe I have seen that apple,
或者说装着它的盒子
or the box that contains it...
在约翰 奥尔登的房子里
In the house of John Alden.
谁啊
Yes?
麦哲牧师
Reverend Mather?
我知道已经晚了
I know it is late.
你出来干什么
What are you doing out?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不知道还能找谁
I didn't know who else to turn to.
你是唯一一个可以帮我的人
You are the only one who can help me.
是啊 然后你就明智的来找我了
Well, then you did the right thing by coming.
呃 我该怎样帮助你呢 还有帮你什么
Uh...How may I help you, and -- and with what?
你认为 变成一个女巫
Do you think it's possible to be a witch
而自己一点儿也不知道 可能吗
and not even know it?
嗯
Um...
我 我认为一个人如果用其灵魂与撒旦结契
I-I think one would know
他一定会知道的
if one had...Deeded one's soul to Satan.
那要是别人用你的灵魂结契了呢
But what if someone deeded it for you?
我向你保证 黑尔小姐
I can assure you, Miss Hale --
不 我想要的不只是你的保证
No. I want more than your assurance.
我想要
I want...
我想让你现在就检查我
I want you to examine me now...
有没有魔鬼的标志
For the mark of the Devil.
然后 你可以向我保证
Then, you may assure me.
我没找到撒旦的记号
I feel no sign of Satan.
你在我看来 似乎 在每个方面
You seem, to me, in every respect,
都没受到魔鬼的烦扰
unmolested by the Devil.
我向你保证 黑尔小姐
I assure you, Miss Hale,
如果你是一个女巫 你会知道的
if you were a witch, you would know it.
不要问丧钟为谁而鸣
Ask not for whom the bell tolls.
它为
It tolls for...
我想知道谁会是第一个
I wonder who will be first.
会是谁呢
Who will it be?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
肯开口的人就不会被烧死
Whoever will speak will not burn.
多简单
Simple.
今晚这里真拥挤 不是吗
Close in here this evening, no?
想想我要去呼吸一下新鲜空气
Think I'll take some air.
我离开以后 考虑一下
While I'm gone, consider...
谁第一个坦白
Which of you will be the first to confess
巫师约翰 奥尔登对你们做了什么
what the witch John Alden did to you.
啊
Aah!
默茜 感谢上帝
Mercy, thank God.
我们坚持不住了
We cannot hold on.
他要对我们逼供
He is going to make us turn.
但是你是要来拯救我们了吗
But you have come to save us?
不 那样不管用
No, it doesn't work that way.
你们还没准备好我的那种穿行
You're not ready to travel as I do.
但请记住 我们仍然为夜之女王服务
But remember, we still serve the queen of the night,
她比我还挂念你们
and she has not forgotten you any more than I have,
会有那么一天 她会来拯救你们
and there will be a day where she will save you.
我保证
I promise.
但是现在
But for now,
你们必须给这老色鬼他想要的
you must give that old goat what he wants.
我非常的害怕他想要的正是我们
I'm terribly afraid it's us he's going to serve up.
这肯定是她计划的一部分
This is surely part of her design.
她的布局比我们的都庞大
Her web is greater than all of ours,
而且她可以看到
and she has a vision,
这片土地将要变成什么样子
a vision of what this land could be.
所以按照麦哲牧师说的做
So do as Reverend Mather asks
在审判时说不利于约翰 奥尔登的证词
and speak against John Alden at the trial.
你实现了几代人梦想的成功
大祭奠就要完成
最后五个祭品即将完成
他们将在月出之时被处以极刑
潘多拉魔盒也将打开
魔盒开启
Malum aperta.
但为什么是约翰 奥尔登
But why John Alden?
他是个牺牲品
你已经牺牲的太多
你将灵魂都献给了这片森林
所以你应该懂的
这样才叫牺牲
有杀戮才有牺牲
但他是无辜的
But he is innocent.
是啊
无辜之血
潘多拉魔盒打开
无数无辜者将丧生
多一个也无妨
这对我来说重要
It matters to me.
你还是个孩子时我们就认识你了
我们养育了你
你就像我们的女儿
你哭泣
如我们哭泣
你流血
如我们流血
现在 泪水即血水
但这些血泪就是我们的武器
可你就是你
没有什么能改变的了
玛丽 听我说
Mary, listen to me.
释放他就能知道你在他心中代表着什么
To free him would reveal what you are to him.
你认为他就会爱你了吗
You think he could love you then?
不要失去他的爱
Do not lose his love.
为了我们去利用它
Use it for all of us.
这就是牺牲
That is the sacrifice.
在所有有关黑巫术的文献中
In all of the literature on witchcraft,
魔盒的意思是邪恶
on malice, malum is "Evil."
所以你告诉我为什么 就这个案子来讲
So you tell me why, in this particular case,
它应该代表苹果
should it signify "Apple"?
我有理由相信这里所提的魔盒
I have reason to believe the malum referred to here
是一个真实的事物
is an actual object,
并且它就在塞勒姆 等着被用来对抗我们
and that object is here in Salem awaiting use against us.
嗯 这真是一个有趣的定理
Well, it's an interesting theorem,
但是 这不符合理性思考的最基本的原则
but...It fails the most basic tenet of rational thinking.
告诉我 两点之间最短的距离是
Tell me -- the shortest distance between two points is...?
-直线 -正确
- A line. - Correct.
常常
And often,
最简单的解释正是最正确的解释
the simplest explanation is the correct explanation.
我只是想阻止盛大仪式
I'm only trying to stop the grand rite.
阻止盛大的仪式吗
Stop the grand rite?
你吗
You?
哦 我的儿啊 年少轻狂啊
Oh, my, the arrogance of youth.
那你知道如何阻止吗
Would you even know how to stop it?
代价又是什么
And at what cost?
或者你想不想听听一个
Or would you like to hear from one
曾经真的成功阻止了并且付出了代价的人怎么说吗
who actually has stopped it and has paid the cost?
你吗
You?
我从不知道
I never knew.
很多年前
Many years ago.
在马尔堡
In marburg.
你还只是个婴儿
You were still just a-a baby.
德国巫师 哦
The German witches, oh,
远远比埃塞克斯巫师更为猖狂
far bolder than even the essex witches.
他们企图举行盛大的仪式
They attempted the grand rite.
一个月内 十二个孩子消失了
Within the space of a month, a dozen children disappeared.
他们的尸体被发现时已血尽干枯
Their bodies were found bled dry.
他们无辜的血浸湿了地面
Their innocent blood soaked the ground.
满月临近时 更多孩子不见了
And as the full moon approached, more children disappeared,
我知道大仪式即将完成
and I knew the grand rite was nearing its completion.
所以当其他人都在找孩子的时候
So while others searched for the children,
我在搜捕巫师
I hunted the witch.
然后我找到了他
And I found him.
他外表是一个6岁的女孩
He had taken the appearance of a 6-year-old girl,
但我知道他不是什么女孩
but I knew this was no girl.
那就是他
It was him.
我用双手掐住她
And I strangled her with my bare hands.
当生命从那个身体流逝时
And as the life left that body,
魔鬼伸手抢夺女孩的身体
the Devil reached out and snatched the body,
但我没有松手
but I held on.
我一定要他再也回不去他的地狱老家
I was determined that he should not return to his home in hell.
然后我的双手陷入了滚沸的黑色沥青里
And my hands were plunged into the boiling black tar.
是地狱之火
Hellfire.
这双手已经真切地触到了地狱
These hands have actually touched hell.
而且它们依然炙烤着我
And they burn me still.
但是宏大的仪式会停止吗
But the grand rite was averted?
确实是只有一种方法可以停止那个宏大的仪式
There really is only one way to stop the grand rite.
必须要有一个人在月亮升起，仪式结束以前
One must kill the witch that began it
杀了开启仪式的巫师
before the moonrise that ends it.
在这种情况下
In this case
杀了约翰 奥尔登
kill John Alden.
众人皆知
It's no secret
约翰 奥尔登对我们有着冷酷而坚定的仇恨
that John Alden has a cold and a willful hatred for us,
就因为我们所信仰的一切
for everything we believe
以及我们圣徒组成的清教徒团体
and for our puritan community of saints.
正是由此
And so, it was
年轻的约翰 奥尔登才与塞勒姆切断联系
that a young John Alden severed himself from Salem
并怀着一颗没有留恋 没有信仰 没有爱的心
and, rootless, faithless, and loveless,
投身到了战争的残酷考验中
cast himself into the crucible of war,
结果他在战争中被野蛮的印第安人俘虏
where he was captured by the heathen Indians.
从此他心中邪恶的种子 已经长出了一个坚硬而恶毒的外壳的种子
And that seed of evil within, already a hard and vicious knot,
找到了茁壮成长的沃土
found fertile ground in which to flourish.
那些愤怒恐怖的神灵的野蛮奴仆们
And the savage servants of the angry, eldritch gods,
他们将奥尔登视作来自撒旦的礼物
they saw in Alden a gift from Satan,
一件充满能量又邪恶
a powerful and vicious weapon
在他们绝望的战争中用来对付我们的武器
to be used in their hopeless war against us.
所以 因为他对我们的仇恨
And so, because of his hatred for us
对一个背叛了他的人的仇恨
and his hatred for one he felt had betrayed him,
他的确变成了一件充满能量而又邪恶的武器
a powerful and a vicious weapon he became.
先生 这纯粹是想象
Sir, this is pure fancy,
赤裸裸的臆想
bald conjecture.
你根本不知道那些
You have no idea what may
曾经发生在奥尔登长官身上的事
or may not have happened to Captain Alden
无论是在他为我们所有人的生命而与印第安人奋战时的事
while fighting for all our lives against the Indians
还是他被印第安人俘虏时的事
or when he was held their captive.
好吧 那么 让他说说看
Well, then, let him speak.
让奥尔登在这里现在就告诉我们
Let Alden tell us here and now
你在野蛮人的领地里失踪了那么久
exactly what transpired during that long period of time
到底发生了什么事情
when you were lost amongst the savages.
说啊 你
Speak, man.
说啊
Speak!
不说吗
No?
那么多年 他干了什么呢
All those years, what could he have been doing?
我来告诉你们
I will tell you.
就像约伯记中所写的撒旦一样
Like Satan in the book of job,
他在土地上来回地走动
he was walking to and fro upon the earth
操纵着怨恨的工具
mastering the tools of malice,
学习着黑暗的法术
learning the dark art
这些法术让他可以远距离地派遣魔鬼的巫使听他的指令
of sending demonic familiars to do his bidding at a distance.
你们可以观察到 这儿 在他的脖子上
You will observe, here, upon his neck...
有一块像铁一样坚硬 并有一个洞的肿块
An iron-hard, raised lump with a hole,
他就是通过这儿喂养他的巫使
and it was here where he suckles his familiars.
这是你最后一次笑了
You will not laugh again.
我敢保证你已经笑了很多次
I'm sure you have laughed many times to think how,
就在这位忠诚的年轻妻子的面前
beneath the very nose of a devoted young wife,
你想着怎么把我们的领导者 曾经充满活力的乔治 西布利
you turned our leader, a once robust George Sibley,
推进痛苦的折磨中的时候
into a suffering heap that he is today.
在你摧毁了我们社区的顶梁柱之后
And after you had undermined the pillar of our community,
你发动了一场恐怖战役
you unleashed a campaign of terror.
就是奥尔登带来了幽灵的恐惧 黑夜的女巫
It was Alden who projected that specter of dread, the night hag,
来恐吓默茜 露易丝
to terrorize Mercy Lewis.
你们会问 为什么 为什么是默茜 露易丝
And you will ask, "Why? Why Mercy Lewis?"
嗯 可能是因为她的父亲 好人牧师露易丝
Well, perhaps it was because her father, the good Reverend Lewis,
娶了奥尔登那苦恋而未得到的情人
married Alden's bitterly lost love to a hated rival,
又或者只是为了表明塞勒姆镇无人能够幸免
or perhaps it was just to show that no one in Salem is safe,
即便她是牧师的女儿
not even the daughter of a blessed Reverend.
柯顿
Cotton!
你照顾过默茜 露易丝
You attended Mercy Lewis.
你对她的艰难处境没有怀疑
You had no doubt as to what ailed her.
她确实是受到了幽灵的攻击
She was indeed under spectral attack,
但是奥尔顿长官
but Captain Alden --
奥尔顿长官 他说什么
Captain Alden -- what did he say
当他看到如此的攻击时
when he witnessed such an attack?
他对此有些怀疑
He cast some doubt upon it.
一些怀疑
Some doubt!
有人告诉我
I am told...
他说它是
He said it was...
屁
"Bullshit."
他还说祈祷是没有用的
And he said that prayers were worthless.
祈祷 无用
Prayer? Worthless?
问问你们自己
Ask yourselves --
每次我们意图抓住和阻止一个巫师时
every time we have attempted to catch and stop a witch,
是谁站出来保护他们
who has risen up to defend them?
是独自混在我们之中 一次又一次地和我们作对
Who alone among us, in encounter, time after time,
而巫术对他总是毫发无伤
with witches has emerged with nary a scratch upon him?
当乔治 西布利死的时候他说了谁的名字
Whose name was on Giles Corey's lips as he died?
谁宣称他在坟墓中能够看到在座的每个人
Who has proclaimed that he will see every man here in his grave?
又是谁 甚至在明明她创造出的怪物时
And who stood up to defend Bridget bishop
也出头保护布里吉特主教
even in the very sight of the monstrosity she had created?
我向你们发誓
I swear to you
这个人每次开口 都是对自己的谴责
this man condemns himself every time he opens his mouth.
就像撒旦在伊甸园中
And like Satan in the garden of eden,
约翰 奥尔登明白女人们
John Alden understands that women are the open doorway
是邪恶得以毒害我们的通道
through which evil enters to poison us all.
多少女性 年轻或年老的 好的或坏的
How many women, young and old, good and bad,
都被奥尔登迷惑了
has Alden bewitched?
有人见到约翰 奥尔登甚至想勾引
It has been seen that John Alden attempted to seduce
这里最高贵的女性
even the highest women in the land.
玛丽 西布利
Mary Sibley.
被告是否强行进入了你的房子
Did not the accused forcibly enter your house,
而且 竟然还进入了你的闺房 就是在那个死亡的夜晚
nay, into your very boudoir, in the dead of night?
我会允许那种事情吗
Would I allow such a thing?
我不知道
I do not know.
但是你的仆人已经证实了
But your servant man has testified
奥尔登在那天晚上确实强行进入了你的房子
that Alden did indeed forcibly make entry in the night.
他来讨论政治
He came to discuss politics.
- 政治 - 确实
- Politics? - Indeed.
他来阐述他的意图
To announce his intention
他想在选举理事会里得到他父亲的席位
to take his father's seat on the select board.
在半夜吗
In the middle of the night?
黑尔小姐
Miss Hale.
被告被发现在公共场合强吻你
The accused was seen kissing you forcibly in public.
这不是你的错
There is no blame attached to you.
你只是一个 一个柔弱又没有反抗能力的姑娘
You are a -- a slight and defenseless slip of a girl.
但是你否认这个吗
But do you deny it?
不否认
He did.
他强吻了
约翰 奥尔登曾经是 现在也是
A snake in the grass is what John Alden was
草地里的那条蛇
and what John Alden is.
当他不想再诱惑那些比他优秀的人的时候
And when he was not attempting to seduce his betters,
就是他的那没有人性的欲望得到满足的时候
he was satiating his own inhuman lusts
那时候 他手下的女巫们所开的妓院
in roomfuls of whores
满屋子都是妓女
in the brothel run by his very own witches.
而且 我想 最坏的便是 塞勒姆镇里温柔年轻的处女们
And, worst of all, I think, the tender, young maidens of Salem,
都会抢着成为他弯折的道路上受害者
so eager to fall prey to his serpentine ways.
默茜告诉我们就是 就是约翰 奥尔登
Mercy told us it was -- it was John Alden
藏进 进了黑夜之中
who came I-in the shadows in the night,
然后他 他亲吻玩弄了她身体的每一个地方
that he -- he kissed and licked and bit every part of her.
他迷惑了她所以她不会说出他的名字
But he bewitched her so she might not name his name
但是她可以将一切归咎于女巫
but she might blame all on the hag.
他用幽灵的形态和她做爱了
He took her in the night in spectral form
并将她的身体和灵魂献给了魔鬼
and gave her body and soul to the Devil himself.
她 她在事后用 用魔法的伎俩
And she -- she drew us in after that
将我们引诱进去
w-with magical tricks a-and games.
然后 很快地 我们在树林里和他跳舞
And, soon, we were dancing in the woods with him,
我们在那里互相抚摸对方 一个接一个地
where we touched each other and, one after the other,
和他上床了
laid with him.
真的吗
Really?
你们所有人
All of you?
你是说 艾米丽
Are you saying, Emily...
你不是处女了吗
That you are not a maiden?
我是否可以检查你
If I were to examine you,
让这里其中一个女人检查你
have one of the women here examine you...
他们就会发现你是否真的不再纯洁了
They would find that you are not intact?
他 他当时用的是舌头和手指
He -- he has tongue and fingers
以及一些不可见的让人 让人快乐的工具
and invisible instruments of -- of pleasure.
哦
Ah.
但是 我 我当时闭着眼睛的
But I-I had my eyes closed.
我不知道他干了什么
I don't know what he did.
这些是幻觉
These are phantasms,
思想组成的幻觉
fabrications of the mind.
我们当中的哪一个
And who here among us has not had,
即使是无意的 没有一些头脑发热的想法
even involuntarily, some heated thoughts?
这个姑娘被那些幻觉控制了
This girl has been overwhelmed by them.
尤其是她面对我父亲对她实施的
Especially in the face of extreme torture
惨无人道的折磨的时候
by my own father.
当一个人被放到刑架上 受到死亡威胁时
Put to the rack, threatened with death,
即便是一个无辜的女孩都可能认为自己是女巫
even an innocent girl might think herself a witch,
她周围的任何男人都是魔鬼
and any man around her a Devil.
我郑重地告诉你 你今天在这里看到的每一件事情
I submit to you that everything you have seen here today
都是因为你受到了本该被质疑的折磨
is the result of torture worthy of the inquisition!
到底是谁真正地暴力虐待了女人们
Who is it who has really violated women?
约翰 奥尔登吗
John Alden?
还是某个掌握
Or one who possesses...
并使用了
And uses...
这种工具的人
Tools such as this?!
你怎么这么大胆
How dare you?
不 先生 你怎么这么大胆
No, sir! How dare you?!
这场庭审今天暂停
This session is suspended for the day!
我们会在大家情绪稳定下来后恢复庭审
We will resume in the morning when tempers have cooled.
整个镇子都想吊死我
The whole town wants to hang me
好像我是一个怪物
like I'm some kind of monster,
好像我真的掌握了一些黑暗的魔力
like I possess some dark, magic power.
你确实如此啊
And you do.
噢 你不会也想吧
Oh, not you, too.
不
No.
我不相信你是个巫师
Don't believe you're a witch.
但是我相信你拥有黑暗的魔力
But I do believe you possess something of dark, magic power.
潘多拉魔盒在哪里
Where is the malum?
什么
What?
那个盒子
The box.
你找到的那个
The box you found
能够引诱地狱的巫师去你的房子的盒子
that lured that infernal witch to your house.
为什么
Why?
我相信它就是传说中的魔盒
I believe it is the fabled malum,
就是开启仪式的钥匙
the key to the grand rite.
这些更多是你看的书里的废话吧
This more of your book nonsense?
那个盒子被图画覆盖
That box covered in images --
我相信它是女巫们最强大的武器
I believe it is the greatest weapon of the witches,
它包含一种
that it contains some kind of
超自然的破坏力量
supernatural agent of destruction
当仪式完成时 就会展现出来
which will open when the grand rite is completed,
对我们宣判 就像
releasing its doom upon us like...
就像潘多拉的神话一样
Like the myth of pandora.
想想吧 如果那东西就如你所说的一样
Look, if that thing is what you say it is,
并且你的父亲知道我拥有它
and your father knows that I have it,
那这就是我棺材上的最后一颗钉子了
that is the final nail in my coffin.
那如果这是我们唯一的机会呢
And what if it's the only chance we have?
它在贾尔斯那儿
Giles has it.
贾尔斯
Giles?
贾尔斯 科里 已经死了
Giles Corey is dead.
我把它埋在他的坟墓里了
And I buried it in his grave.
你知道该怎么用它吗
You know what to do with it?
父亲 我必须和你谈谈
Father, I must speak to you.
现在行了啊
What now?
翅膀长硬了
More disrespect?
不
No.
父亲大人
Sir.
我仍然认为你所做的完全是错误的
I still think what you do is fundamentally wrong,
一定还有另外的方法 但
that there must be other ways, but...
我害怕
I am afraid.
怕得要死
Deathly afraid.
我怕 尽管我们所用的方法不同
I fear, while we disagree on methods,
我们都决心停止这场盛大的仪式
we are both determined to stop the grand rite.
嗯哼
Well...
我很高兴你至少承认了这点
I'm gratified that you at least acknowledge that.
盒子在这里
The malum is here.
或者是
Or was.
我看见它了
I saw it.
我甚至 碰过它了
I touched it, even.
真的
Indeed?
那它现在在哪
Then where is it?
我不知道
I don't know.
嗯哼
Well...
告诉我你在哪看见的
Tell me where you saw it.
在约翰 奥尔登的房子
In John Alden's house.
父亲 你不理解
Father, you don't understand.
他在帮我
He was helping me.
就是他困住了女巫并和我一起把女巫
It was he who trapped the witch and carried her with me
带到树林审问并杀了她
to the woods to question and kill her.
你不理解
You don't understand.
在某些方面 女巫和我们不一样
In some respects, the witches are not unlike us.
他们有派系 他们有权力斗争
They have factions. They have power struggles.
你的朋友奥尔登不是在试图抓住女巫
Your friend Alden was not trying to catch a witch.
他只是在消除竞争对手
He was eliminating a rival.
你被你自己的疑问蒙蔽了双眼
You are blinded by your own doubt,
这会毁了你
and it will destroy you!
如果我同意你的话
If I grant you
那就有一种可能奥尔登是无罪的
that there is a possibility that Alden is innocent,
你就不能承认这种
can you not grant the possibility
十分之一 不 百分之一的可能性
that there is a 1 in 10, nay, a 1 in 100 chance
我是对的
that I am right?!
如果我是对的 数千人将灭亡
And if I am, thousands will perish.
国家会衰落
The nation itself may fall.
你能承担那种可能性吗 我不能
Can we take that chance? I cannot.
你能吗
Can you?
我告诉你 柯顿
I tell you, Cotton,
你不知道这个男人几乎也是你认为你所做的
you do not know this man nearly as well as you think you do.
我搜查了吉尔斯科里的坟墓
I searched Giles Corey's grave.
盒子不在那里
The malum wasn't there.
那不可能 是我亲手埋了它的
That's impossible. I buried it myself.
还有谁看见了
Who else knew?
没有人
No one.
只有你
Just you.
而且你不相信我
And you don't believe me.
我不知道该相信什么
I'm not sure what to believe.
我只相信两样东西
I am certain only of two things.
我们一生也许就寄托在
All our lives may depend on
找到并销毁那盒子上
finding and destroying the malum.
还有
And?
还有你对我更加不坦诚了
And you are being less than honest with me.
我已经把一切都告诉你了
I've told you everything.
到底还要说什么
What the hell is going on?!
醒醒吧
- Get up.
那些女孩是无辜的
Those girls are innocent!
不
No!
原谅我
Forgive me!
那是我唯一后悔的事 对你撒谎
It's the only thing I regret -- lying about you!
看 我知道他们对你做了什么
Look, I know what they did to you.
那不是你的错
It's not your fault.
来我这
Get over here!
去你妈的
Damn you!
做些什么吧她们只是群女孩子
Do something! They're just girls!
你 你答应过会饶恕我们的
You! You promised you'd spare us!
这个世界我将用火结束你的生命
I am sparing you the flames of this world
下个世界你还是要受到火的炼狱
and of the next.
你不会痛苦太久的
You will not suffer long.
我将会给你腿上戴上宽恕的铁链
A full measure of Mercy is being added to your legs.
放我过去
Let go of me!
父亲 你撒了谎
Father, you lied!
你答应过这些女孩会
You promised these girls they wouldn't --
点火
Burn.
没有人
Nor shall they.
别这样 父亲
Don't do this, father.
这会有帮助吗
How can this possibly help?
你过说她们都是受害者
You said yourself they were victims!
很遗憾但是是事实
Sad but true.
但她们被感染了 被女巫
But they're tainted... By the Devil.
我恐怕她们带走了他的种子
I fear they carry his very seed.
你为什么那么肯定
How can you be certain?
我很肯定
I am certain.
我肯定这个威胁是指向塞勒姆的
I am certain of the threat they pose to Salem,
就像我肯定你的软弱构成了威胁
just as I am certain that your weakness poses a threat.
但总之 我很肯定
But above all, I am certain that,
就像一个外科医生 我别无选择只能切除
like a surgeon, I have no choice but to cut out
恶性肿瘤
the malignant manifestation of malice
在它进一步扩散之前
before it can spread any further.
不 停下
No! Stop!
请帮帮我 求你了 求你了
Please help me! Please! Please!
回去
Get back!
点火
Burn in hell!
让她们燃烧
Let them burn!
默茜
Mercy!
你在哪里
Where are you?!
默茜
Mercy!
这是什么
What is it?
多利 发生什么了
Dollie, what has happened?
艾米丽 伊丽莎白 苏珊娜 和
Emily, Elizabeth, Susanna, and charity --
因克里斯麦哲把她们都绞死了
Increase Mather has hung them all.
你发誓她们会安全的
You swore that they would be safe,
但现在她们死了
but they're dead!
她们所有人都死了
All of them have been killed!
你说过你的主人会保护我们的
You said your master would protect us,
但她什么都没做
and she did nothing!
回到塞勒姆吧
Go back to Salem.
把年轻人
Gather the young,
穷人和受苦的人聚集起来
the poor, the suffering.
他们会成为我们的军队
They will be our army.
新的一天就在我们眼前
A new day is upon us.
但新的一天需要
And that new day demands
一个新的黑夜女王
a new queen of the night!
我知道你们很多人觉得这难以接受
I know that so many of you find it hard to accept,
不敢相信约翰奥尔登
impossible to believe that John Alden,
我们造物者的一个儿子 一个勇敢的战士为了保护我们
son of one of our founders and a brave soldier in our defense,
因为邪恶的巫术而有罪
is guilty of malefic witchcraft.
很好
Fine.
Fine!
不管你们抛弃不抛弃你们的信仰 这都不重要
Suspend your belief or not. It doesn't matter.
只有一件事是重要的 那就是 奥尔登被判是有罪的
The only thing that matters is that Alden...Be convicted
事实上他
and sentenced for what he truly is,
是一个叛徒和杀人犯
a traitor and a murderer.
什么
What?
你到底在说什么
Whatever do you mean?
我认为尽管奥尔登一直和印第安人在一起
I submit that while John Alden was with the Indians,
而且不只是和他们一起共事
he not only took up with them.
他建立起了反对他们自己人的军队
He took up arms against his own people,
在自己的国家屠宰民兵
slaughtering militiamen in his own company,
善良的新英格兰人 每个人
good new england men, every one of them.
我发誓这是真的
I swear this to be true.
我恐怕约翰奥尔登会否认这些事实
And I dare John Alden to deny it!
我恐怕你不敢告诉我
I dare you to tell me
你把自己的脸化成一个印第安异教徒
that you did not paint your face as a heathen Indian
并且在你自己的国家粉碎人的头骨
and smash the skulls of men in your own company!
胡说八道
Outrageous accusations!
你到底是怎么说出这些胡话的
Wherever did you find such nonsense?
我发誓这些证词来自奴隶缇图芭
I have sworn testimony from the slave Tituba!
哼
Aha!
全是谎话和幻想
Lies and fantasies.
谎话 上尉
Lies? Captain?
幻想
Fantasies?
你想申辩吗
Do you dispute the charges?
说
Speak.
上尉 这些都是真的吗
Captain...Is this all true?
在这里每一个理智尚存的人都知道我不是巫师
Every sane man in this place knows I ain't a witch.
你是背叛者吗
Are you a traitor?
你是杀人犯吗
Are you a murderer?
混蛋 约翰 快回答他啊
Damn you, John. Answer him.
那么 大家看见了吧
So, you see...
有时候 沉默就是最有说服力的认罪
Sometimes, silence can be the most eloquent confession of all.
我从不怀疑 没有一丝一毫怀疑过
I have no doubt, not a sliver of a doubt,
约翰 奥尔登是一个巫师
that John Alden is a witch.
但是 既是我不是必须这么做
But...Even had I not...
我还是坚持
I would still maintain
要为了他无法否认的罪行 施以绞刑
that he must hang for crimes he will not deny.
你们也应该这么想
And nor should you.
看在上帝的份上 告诉我 我父亲说错了
For God's sake, tell me my father is wrong.
告诉我 你不是他说的那样的
Tell me you are not the man he says you are.
这现在还重要吗
What does it matter now?
对我来说很重要
It matters to me --
你到底有没有愚弄我这么久
whether you duped me all this time.
你确定你想要真相吗
Are you sure you want the truth?
你真他妈的确定
Are you really damn sure
你知道善与恶的区别吗
you know the difference between good and evil?
因为你是个清教徒
'Cause you puritans,
你会觉得世界上不是黑就是白
you think the world is just black and white.
但如果这世界的真相就是灰色的呢
What if the truth of the world is that it's nothing but gray?
在大沼泽之战之后
After the battle of the great swamp,
我生死不明被所有人抛弃了
I was left for dead.
但是我被莫霍克人所找到
But I was found by the mohawk --
不是跟我们打仗的那些印第安人 不
not the Indians we fought, no.
莫霍克人不是我们的盟友
The mohawk aren't our friends,
但是他们是与我们打仗的阿布纳基人的敌人
but they are the enemies of the abenaki we fight.
说实在的 我
In all honesty, I...
我不认为我能理解他们为什么会救我
I don't think I'll ever understand why they saved me.
直到现在对我来说都是个迷
It is a mystery to me to this day.
你父亲找到的伤疤
The scar your old man found
他说是喂养一个奴仆所留下的
he said was from feeding a familiar?
那其实是是从我身体里取出铅弹
That was from digging a ball of lead out of me
并且用他们的药治愈我留下的
and healing it with their medicines.
他们留下你要求赎金吗
They held you for ransom?
不
No.
他们用善意和尊敬对待我
They treated me with kindness and respect.
他们的圣人对我很感兴趣
And their holy men took an interest in me.
我都不确定为什么 或是他在透过我看见了什么
I'm not even sure why or what he saw in me,
但如果不是他
but if he hadn't...
我早就死了
I'd be dead.
所以我在他们之间生活
So I lived amongst them.
我分享了他们的食物和庇护
I shared their food and their shelter.
我甚至和他们一起打猎
I even hunted with them.
有一天 我和几个勇者打猎回来
One day, me and a few braves returned from a hunt
发现整个村子都被烧成了灰烬只剩下废墟
to find the village had been burned to the ground.
女人和孩子们 都散落在村庄各地
The women and the children, they're all scattered
像是死了的、飘落的树叶 他们被屠杀了
like dead, fallen leaves, slaughtered.
被阿布纳基人吗
By the abenaki?
不是的
No.
是军队
Militia.
我们的军队
Our militia.
他们从不屑于
Couldn't even be bothered
分辨不同的印第安人的村落
to tell one Indian tribe from another.
血红色的雾从我心中升起
A red fog descended upon me,
这雾不曾消散 直到我穿过树林
and it did not lift until I ran through those woods
杀死了所有那些混蛋
and killed every one of those bastards,
所有人 除了我
everyone but one.
对于那件事 我要纠正的是 就是那晚我找到了盒子
And that I corrected the night I found the box.
潘多拉之盒吗
And the malum?
我对它一无所知
I didn't know nothing about that.
你说那就是女巫们一直渴望得到的东西
You said it was something that the witches wanted badly.
当我们在树林里跟丢了那个女巫的时候
When we lost that witch in the woods,
我想到最好还是把它藏起来
I thought it was best to hide it,
所有 就像我告诉你的那样 我把它和吉尔斯一起埋了
so, like I told you, I buried it with Giles.
那么 就是其他人又把它拿了出来
Well, then someone unburied it.
也许你什么也不必担心
Maybe you have nothing to worry about, then,
因为照你父亲所说
because according to your father,
我就是幕后的巫师
I am the witch behind it.
你唯一要做的就是绞死我
So, all you have to do is hang me,
然后一切都会变好的
and then everything will be just fine.
我不能理解的是
What I can't figure out,
我想要推测的是
what I am trying to surmise,
过了这么久
is, after all of this,
经过了我们所遇见的一切
after everything we've been through --
你是需要一个朋友 还是一个兵卒
you needed a friend or a pawn?
哭泣什么忙也帮不了
Weeping don't help.
相信我
Trust me.
我做了我应该做的
Done my fair share.
以撒
Isaac.
上帝啊 你还在流血
God, you're still bleeding.
在这里 谁不会呢
Around here, who ain't?
我到底做了什么
What have I done?
我知道这些都不是你的错
I know none of this is your fault,
都是我的错
and all of it's mine.
那天他正要离开镇上
He was on his way out of town that day.
是我阻止了他
I stopped him.
如果不是我的话 他早就离开了
If it weren't for me, he'd be long gone.
这些事都不会发生了
None of this would have happened.
也许明天早上还得是我拉绳子绞死他
I might as well pull the rope myself in the morning.
还是我杀死了约翰 奥尔登
I've as good as killed John Alden.
但是你
But you...
你可以救他
You can save him.
我不能 我不能
I can't. I can't!
你是玛丽
You're Mary.
你是玛丽啊
他们叫你玛丽 西布里
They all call you Mary Sibley.
你知道我怎么叫你吗
Do you know what I call you
在我脑中 对我自己 心灵深处
in my head, to myself, in my heart?
神奇玛丽
"Magic Mary."
你总是很神奇
You were always magic,
即使我们都还是小豆芽菜的时候
even back when we was just sprouts.
你无所不能
And you could do anything --
一直如此
always could.
你只需要等到事态变得一团糟
You just have to want it bad enough.
然后你再出场
And you do.
不是吗
Don't you?
你确实希望约翰 奥尔登活着
You do want John Alden to live.
你是怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
他们明天就会把你绞死
They will hang you tomorrow.
他们
"They"?
是啊 你难道不也是其中之一嘛  西布利女士
Well, aren't you one of them, Mrs. Sibley?
有的时候  我也不记得我是谁
Sometimes, I no longer remember who I am.
但我知道你是谁
But I know who you are
一个无辜的人
an innocent man.
正相反
Hardly.
这真是让人哭笑不得
Now it's almost funny.
塞勒姆终于给真真正正犯罪的人
Salem finally sentenced someone to die
判下了死刑
for something they've actually done.
回家吧 玛丽
Go home, Mary.
过你自己的生活去  西布利夫人
Go back to your life, Mrs. Sibley.
你就是我的生活
You are my life.
好吧 现在似乎有点晚了
Well, it's a little late for that thought.
我不会让你上绞刑架的
I'll not let you hang.
我可以救你
I can save you.
塞勒姆的好人
The good people of Salem,
也就是那些我曾试图拯救的人
the people I've been trying to save,
他们都想让我死
they all want me dead.
他们认为我就是恶魔的本体
They think I'm the Devil himself.
我不是恶魔
I'm no Devil.
但我确实为背叛而感到愧疚
But I am guilty of treason...
也包括谋杀
And murder.
我已经做好了为此上绞刑架的准备
And I'm ready to hang for it.
况且
Besides...
我也心累了
I'm awfully tired.
不能和你一起活着 很累
Tired of living without you.
总有办法能使我们继续在一起
There's still a way for us to be together.
已经结束了
It's over.
你哪根筋搭错了
What's wrong with you?
你跟镇里的其他人一样都疯了吗
Have you gone mad like everyone else in this town?
约翰 我向你保证
John, I promise you --
不 别说什么保证
No, don't.
我们俩都不是会信守承诺的人  所以别信誓旦旦了
Neither of us is very good with promises, so no more vows.
你听我说
Listen to me.
我在听
I am listening to you,
可你说的都是无稽之谈
and you aren't making any sense.
看看周围
Look around you.
都是石头做得四壁
These are stone walls.
封掉的窗
Barred windows,
铁做得门
an iron door.
现在我们头顶上悬着一根粗绳子 分分钟要我命
Right above us, a thick rope awaiting my neck.
这是铁的事实
Those are the stubborn facts.
即使爱得多深
And all the love in the world
也不能改变现在的这种局面 哪怕一点点
can't change a single one of them.
你错了
You're wrong.
爱比现实更强大  爱无坚不摧
Love is stronger than fact, stronger than everything.
但我告诉你 约翰
But I tell you, John,
这个世界上还是有这么块属于我们的地方
there is still a place for us in this world.
只有在梦里才有
Only in dreams.
行 那就这样吧
All right, then.
最后一次
One last time...
我们一起入梦
Dream with me.